BU records: First Families of Baylor Club, Inclusive: 1940-1951, Bulk: 1940-1942
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU records: First Families of Baylor Club
Inclusive: 1940-1951, Bulk: 1940-1942
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/222
First Families of Baylor Club
1 document box
The BU Records: First Families of Baylor Club includes minutes, correspondence, membership lists, and other materials. The club was a student organization that Baylor students could join if they had a previous relative attend Baylor.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
The First Families of Baylor Club was a student club at Baylor University during the 1940’s. Students could join the club if they had a relative, usually their grandfather, grandmother, father, or mother, who attended Baylor. The club seemed to be most active in the 1940s and 1950s. There seemed to be a definite transition in the types of events the club held. In the 1940s, the club was interested in locating and preserving historical materials, but by the 1950s, the club had transitioned to more traditional student activities, such as a roller-skating parties and other social events. There is no known connection between the club and the annual First Families of Baylor Award given by the university.
Scope and Content
The BU Records: First Families of Baylor Club contains material of the First Families of Baylor Club, a student club at Baylor University. Students who had previous family members attend Baylor were eligible to join. This collection includes year-by-year members list ranging from 1940-1951, administration letters verifying student membership, newspaper clippings of First Families of Baylor Club events, meeting notes, and copies of the Baylor Century from 1940 and 1941 which included photos of members. This collection does not contain information related to the creation of the First Families of Baylor Club nor when it ceased to be a Baylor student organization.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series: Administrative and Print Material. Administrative includes four folders of First Families of Baylor Club members list, including the students’ relative(s) who attended Baylor. The series also includes letters, application materials, meeting notes, and the First Families of Baylor Club constitution.
Print Material includes newspaper clippings, envelopes and invitations to First Families of Baylor Club events, and two copies of the Baylor Century.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/222. Acquired 0-00-00
Related Resources
Related references
"FFB Sponsors First Weekly Union Building Skating Party." Daily Lariat. Waco, Texas: 1952 April 16. Accessed 2021 January 26.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Records and correspondence.; Baylor University -- Students -- Correspondence.; Baylor University -- Students.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Membership lists.; Minutes (Records)
- Administrative, 1940-1951; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains membership lists, minutes, and other administrative materials from the First Families of Baylor Club. This series is in average condition.
  - Membership List 1, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Membership List 2, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership List 3, circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership List 4, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1940-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Application Materials and Dues, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1941-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notes, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - First Families of Baylor Club Constitution and Baylor Saga, circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Print Material, 1940-1948; 2
  This series contains clippings, invitations, and other print materials to do with the First Families of Baylor Club. This series is in poor condition.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1942-1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Invitations, 1942 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Baylor Century, 1940 November-1941 January (Box 1, Folder 12)